LEONARDO BONAVENTURA

Front-end developer | UI developer | Javascript developer

SUMMARY

Front-end developer with almost 2 years of experience in building complex, well-tested, multi-page, responsive user interfaces using HTML, CSS, TypeScript, and React. Worked in international teams of 10+ people using agile methodologies like Kanban and Scrum and paying attention to code quality and delivering issue-free products to the user. Looking for new opportunities to grow professionally

WORK EXPERIENCE

July 2022 - Present | Bitrock srl

Front-end developer

- Worked as a contractor in international teams (client list included Moneyfarm, a fintech company specializing in investment advisory)
- Participated in the implementation of client's UI requests
- Implemented the UI of numerous features in autonomy using react, typescript, xstate, formik, react-router, and react query
- Contributed to developing custom component libraries using styled-components and storybook
- Tested the application using jest and react testing library for unit test and Cypress for integration / end-to-end tests
- Configured component testing touching Cypress, Webpack, Typescript, and Jest configuration files
- Sanified a prone-to-fail CI/CD pipeline caused by flaky tests
- · Solved numerous bugs and UI glitches
- · Refactored parts of the codebase by applying clean code practices
- Maintained the JIRA board updated writing descriptions, comments and story points
- Presented results of an R&D investigation about machine learning and Knime Software to the entire department of 30+ people

December 2021 - June 2022 | Id3aLab @ Unimib

Front-end developer

- Worked on a project funded by Regione Lombardia whose aim was to allow users to create and explore journeys along the cultural heritage of the Italian region.
- Developed the UI of the "search journey" feature using HTML, CSS, javascript, and react
- · Managed the retrieval of the data from the backend using REST API and redux
- Handled the visualization data in different forms (e.g. card grid, google maps, tube map) using MaterialUi, React Google Maps, d3-tubemap
- Defined and implemented the algorithm to dynamically calculate the coordinates for the tube map visualization

EDUCATION

October 2020 - October 2023 | Università degli studi di Milano-Bicocca, Milan

Master's degree in Communication theory and technology

Thesis: "Dictator game and gaze cueing effect: do fair vs unfair economic treatment influence our gaze following behavior?"

October 2017 - October 2020 | Università degli studi di Milano-Bicocca, Milan

Bachelor's degree in Psychological science and techniques

Thesis: "Future self and morality: the relation among future self continuity and moral foundations" (grade: 109/110)



INFO & CONTACTS

Italian

♣ 17 october 1996

⊘ Single

Schleißheimer Str. 216, 80797 München

(+39) 338 790 4050

leo.bo96@gmail.com

leobo96.github.io (Portfolio)

github.com/leobo96

in linkedin.com/in/leonardobonaventura

TECHNICAL SKILLS

Html, CSS, Javascript
React / React.js
Redux
TypeScript
Responsive design
Git
Linux / Command line interface (CLI)
Software Testing (Jest, React testing library,
Cypress, Storybook)
Figma - UX/UI Design
Jira

SOFT SKILLS

Communication Empathy Organization Persuasion Synthesis

LANGUAGES

Italian (mother tongue) English (professional) French (basic)